#最近老婆心情不好
My wife is in a bad mood recently.
#我摘點這個珠子啊
So I pick some this kind of beads,
#串成一串項鏈
to make a necklace for her,
送給她
as a gift,
逗一下她
to please her.
#這個珠子是我們小時候啊
When I was a kid, we used to pick these beads,
#摘來 送給自己喜歡的人的
as, as a gift to the person we liked.
#還小的時候 喜歡誰我就送給誰
I simply gave it to whoever I like when I was small.
#這好多 這個黑黑的就可以了
A lot. These black ones are good enough.
#這很硬的 這個黑黑的
These black ones are very hard.
#你看 這裡也有
Look! Here too.
#等下我們用一根那個
I'll string,
#縫衣服的那個針
string them together,
#串起來
with a sewing needle.
#就可以把它串 串起來 就像一根項鏈一樣
Then I can string, string them together. Just like a necklace.
#現在摘了那麼多
Now I've already picked so many.
#很硬的哦 你看 聽聲音聽上去哦
They're really hard. Look! You can feel it by the sound.
#聽得到
You can hear,
#噹噹噹的響
Dong dong dong
#好多花在這裡
Here're a lot of flowers.
#這個花不要
I don't need the flowers.
#誒呦 踩到水裡面去
Ayo! I stepped into the water.
#你看
Look!
#摘了一口袋
I've picked a whole pocket of beads.
#等下我們用那個
Then I'll string them together,
#縫衣服的針綫啊 把它串起來
by the sewing kit.
#很靚哦 這個
It's beautiful.
#這個針
The needles.
#針我是買回來的哦 (註︰不明白他的意思，所以直譯算了，他究竟想說「我剛買的，不是家中的」，還是「不是兄弟家的」)
I bought the needles.
#你個針 那麼小 這個針眼好小
The needle, is so small, the needle eye is so small.
#現在手都好笨啊
My hands are getting clumsy.
#穿不到的
No, I can't.
#這個 (註︰他應該想說「這個穿不到的」，但感覺得難譯得自然，所以變了一下字眼)
No way.
#換個最大的
How about the one with the largest,
#最大的針眼
largest needle eye.
#現在老眼昏花啦
My eyes are getting blurred recently.
#這個
This one,
#最大的一顆
is the largest.
#先把它關起來 不要跑啦 這個針
Close it tight. Don't drop the needles.
#這個很好穿的 這個
It's easy, with this needle.
#你看 一下就穿進去了
Look! I did it in the first trial.
#應該夠了 這麼長應該夠了
Should be enough. It should be long enough.
#看下能不能串的[SIC]到
See if I can string them together.
#這個
It,
#這個針好像太大啦 穿不過去
it seems that the needle is too big to pass through the beads.
#要換成小針才行
I need a smaller needle.
#這個針太大了 我們要換個小的
This needle is too big. I need to use a smaller one.
#這個針眼好小 我要慢慢的
The needle eye is really small. I need to do it slowly,
#慢慢的穿
really slowly.
#幹嘛廠家不幫我們串好針
Why didn't the dealer get it done for me?
#串好針錢
With the thread on the needle.
#這樣我們拿了就可以用
Then I can use it directly.
#你會不會串
Can you do it?
#你來串
Help me.
#這個眼太小啦
The eye is far too small.
#大的針
The big needle,
#穿不過去
can't pass through the beads.
#就串過去啦
It's a piece of cake for you.
#那麼快
So fast.
#眼睛不好了現在
My eyesight is not as good as before.
#30歲啦
I'm already 30.
#肯定現手機玩太久了
I must be spending too much time on my mobile phone.
#嗯 可以
Um, alright!
#它這已經穿好啦
Then, this part is done.
#這樣子戳的話就很快了
And the rest doesn't take much time.
#你看 一戳就進去了
Just push it in, that's it!
#這個打個結打大一點 等下
The knot here needs to be bigger, otherwise,
#這邊串那邊漏
the beads may drop from this side.
#三個了
Three already.
#戳了下我的手 誒呦
I pierced my finger, hayo!
#這個針錢
Needlework,
#這個公錢活 不好幹啊
needlework is always hard for me.
#還是砍竹子好一點
Chopping bamboo is easier.
#這個一個一個穿 穿的好慢啊
I need to do it one by one. It's so time consuming.
#幹嘛不自己跑進去
Why don't you guys get to the place by yourselves?
#你看 是不是
Look! Right?
#有樣子啦
The shape is here.
#誒呦
Aya!
#戳手了
Pierce my finger
#你看
Look!
#就一串啦
It's a string now.
#還不夠
Still not enough
#就搭一個圈 (註︰以下些自言自語類的，我沒有譯得太準確，因為有些是英文沒有的說法，有當成一個英語人會說的話就算了)
Put them together?
#這個是
Or?
#誒呦 這裡還有
Ayo? I still have some.
#你看
Look!
#很靚了哦
It's beautiful.
#這裡串過去
Put it here.
#等下怎麼套進去呀
How can it be put on?
#那麼小一段
It's so small.
#這個 這邊 這邊不能鎖那麼緊
Here, this side, this side needs to be loosened a bit.
#等一下 等一下我親自幫她掛上去
I'll, I'll put it on for her myself.
#靚不靚 先給我載一下
Is it beautiful? Let me try it first,
#然後再給我老婆載
before giving it to my wife.
#先試一下合不合適
Let me see if it's nice enough first.
#很靚哦
Beautiful!
#她肯定很開心
I'm sure that she'll be very happy.
#是我親自做的
It's hand made by myself.
#外面太陽那麼大
Despite the strong sunlight outside,
#我都給她 給她摘了一個 摘了那麼多珠子
I've still picked a, picked so many beads for her,
#串在一起
for this necklace.
#肯定很喜歡
She will like it.
#嗯
Um!
#果子味
Fruity smell.
#誒呦
Eyo?
#幸好 我以為會掉 不會
Lucky! I though廿 the beads would drop. They won't.
#好啦
Alright!
#今天的視頻到這裡啦
The video ends here.
#晚上我就去送 送給我老婆
I'll give it, give it to my wife tonight.